Finding aid to Office of the President William Allan Neilson files CA.MS.00013
Smith College Archives
Office of President William Allan Neilson Files
1900-1948
Smith College Archives
Neilson, William Allan, 1869-1946.
CA.MS.00013
24.375 linear feet (57 containers)
Willaim Allan Neilson was the third President of Smith College. The Office of President William Allan Neilson files contain official records of the Office of the President including, correspondence, subject files, organization files, and confidential files.
Biographical / Historical
William Allan Neilson served as president of Smithh College for 22 years. Born March 28, 1869, in Doune, Pertshire Scotland, he attended Edinburgh University where he studied philosophy, graduating with honors in 1891. In order to join his brother who emigrated to Canada, Neilson crossed the Atlantic and began teaching in Upper Canada College in Toronto which was a boarding school for young boys.
Deciding that he would prefer to be a scholar than a school master, Neilson went on to Harvard Graduate School in Cambridge, MA where he received his Ph.D. in English in 1898. Upon receiving his Ph.D., Neilson accepted a position as an Associate in English Literature at Bryn Mawr College in Bryn Mawr, PA. Neilson taught at many other fine institutions before settling into the work of an administrator. Harvard, Radcliffe, the Sorbonne, Columbia, Barnard, and the University of California all made use of Neilson's talents at one time or another.
It was during his years as a professor that Neilson distinguished himself as the sort of scholar that an academic institution would wish to guide it. Before coming to Smith, Neilson made a name for himself as a professor devoted to his students' learning. He was the only instructor of Helen Keller's who learned the manual sign language she used for communication. He was also an accomplished writer and editor. Among his writings were Essentials of Poetry (1912)and The Facts about Shakespeare (1913). He also was the editor of Milton's Minor Poems (1899) and Shakespeare's Complete Works (1906).
In 1917, Neilson was offered the Presidency of Smith College. He accepted on the conditions that he would not be obligated to raise money, and that a president's house would be built, conditions the trustees complied with.
Neilson's quick wit that endeared him to student, staff, faculty, and alumnae. At Neilson's final commencement in 1939 Cynthia Walsh recalled one particular instance:
The seniors will especially recall that on May Day when they went to serenade him, his new collie puppy began to bark, not realizing what sweet voices were vying with the birds so early in the morning. When the president stepped out he said, "My dog thinks you're sheep," and the volleys of laughter which greeted this remark quite drowned out the rest: "-but I think you're lambs!"
Neilson's accomplishments included purchasing and building new residences so that all Smith students would live on campus. He was responsible for the building of the Great Quadrangle, purchasing Chapin House, Talbot House, Sessions House, and many others. During Neilson's 22-year term as president, the campus also saw the additions of Sage Music Hall, Scott Gymnasium, Tryon Art Gallery, the Alumnae House, the Infirmary, and the President's house.
Neilson also established the Junior Year in France, Junior Year in Italy, and the Junior Year in Spain Programs. Special Honors, the Smith College Day School, and the School for Social Work were additions that Neilson made to the college.
Neilson continued writing and editing while looking after the well being of 2,000 students. In 1920 he wrote History of English Literature and in 1922 he edited Roads to Knowledge. He also was the editor-in-chief of Webster's New International Dictionary, 2nd edition, 1934.
Scope and Contents
The Office of President William Allan Neilson files document his official duties as president of Smith College. The collection includes correspondence, subject files, organization files, and confidential files. Neilson's collaboration with trustees is demonstrated in the correspondence files. His involvement in the development of the curriculum, alumnae relations, construction of buildings, and the basic running of the college is highlighted in the subject files. Of particular interest in the organization files is information on donors to Smith College. The confidential files document the acquisition of pieces of art for the Smith College gallery.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into four series:
I. Correspondence
II. Organization
III. Subjects
IV. Confidential
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.
Faculty tenure and promotion files, as well as inactive faculty files are closed permanently. Board of Trustees' records are closed permanently. Minutes of the Faculty Council are closed to all except current Smith College Faculty for a period of 75 years following their creation. Student academic records, student disciplinary records, and all records containing FERPA-covered student information are closed during the lifetime of the student. Student records created 100 years or more ago are assumed to be about deceased students. In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source unknown
Smith College -- presidents; Neilson, William Allan, 1869-1946.; Smith College--Presidents.; Smith College. Office of President.
- Series I. Correspondence
  - A-Ad (misc), 1918-39 (Box 364, Folder 1)
  - Abbott, E. J., 1928-29 (Box 364, Folder 2)
  - Abbott, Herbert Vaughan, 1923-27 (Box 364, Folder 3)
  - Abbott, Jere, 1929-39 (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Abbott, Josephine (Dormitzer) '11, 1925-38; undated (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - Abbott, Senda (Berenson), 1929-30 (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - Adams, Elizabeth Kemper, 1918-27 (Box 364, Folder 7)
  - Adler, Herman, 1918-31 (Box 364, Folder 8)
  - Ag-Ali (misc), 1918-39 (Box 364, Folder 9)
  - Ainsworth, Dorothy Sears, 1927-39 (Box 364, Folder 10)
  - Akeley, Mary L. (Mrs. Carl), 1932-33 (Box 364, Folder 11)
  - Albright, R. K., 1928 (Box 364, Folder 12)
  - Alden, Stanley, 1921-27 (Box 364, Folder 13)
  - Aldrich, Amey Owen '95, 1924-28 (Box 364, Folder 14)
  - Aldrich, Betty (Knight) '03, 1931-34; undated (Box 364, Folder 15)
  - All (misc), 1920-39 (Box 364, Folder 16)
  - Allen, Mr. and Mrs. Frank Gates, 1919-33 (Box 364, Folder 17)
  - Alo-And (misc), 1923-39 (Box 364, Folder 18)
  - Ames, John W. and Sarah, 1920-37 (Box 364, Folder 19)
  - Ames, Blanche Ames '99, 1924-25 (Box 364, Folder 20)
  - Anderson, Dorothy May, 1934-35 (Box 364, Folder 21)
  - Anderson, Paul L., 1933-38 (Box 364, Folder 22)
  - Andre, Jessie A. G., 1928-35 (Box 364, Folder 23)
  - Andrews, Hannah Dunlop, 1919-21 (Box 364, Folder 24)
  - Ang-Ar (misc), 1917-39; undated (Box 364, Folder 25)
  - Angell, James R., 1927-37 (Box 364, Folder 26)
  - Armstrong, Jane B., 1935 (Box 364, Folder 27)
  - Arvin, Newton, 1926-39 (Box 364, Folder 28)
  - As-Az (misc), 1920-43 (Box 364, Folder 29)
  - Atwood, Wallace W., 1936-37 (Box 364, Folder 30)
  - Avery, Elizabeth, 1919-29 (Box 364, Folder 31)
  - Aydelotte, Frank and Marie, 1917-36 (Box 364, Folder 32)
  - Ba-Bal (misc), 1918-39; undated (Box 364, Folder 33)
  - Bacon, Dorothy Carolin, 1927-37; undated (Box 364, Folder 34)
  - Bacon, Mr. and Mrs. George W., 1918-35 (Box 364, Folder 35)
  - Baker, Franklin T., 1923-28 (Box 364, Folder 36)
  - Baker, Newton D., 1926-32 (Box 364, Folder 37)
  - Baker, Ray Palmer, 1921-39 (Box 364, Folder 38)
  - Baldwin, Roger N., 1924-25 (Box 364, Folder 39)
  - Baldwin, Ruth S. (Bowles) '87, 1918-34 (Box 364, Folder 40-41)
  - Baldwin, William Henry, 1922; undated (Box 364, Folder 42)
  - Ballinger, Willis H., 1923-26 (Box 364, Folder 43)
  - Bam-Barn (misc), 1920-39; undated (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - Barbour, Amy Louise '91, 1921-37 (Box 365, Folder 2)
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer: Publications, 1926-30 (Box 365, Folder 3)
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer, 1923-28 (Box 365, Folder 4)
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer, 1929 (Box 365, Folder 5)
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer, 1930-37 (Box 365, Folder 6)
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer: Econ and Sociology, 1923-1930 (Box 365, Folder 7)
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer: "Genesis of the World War", 1926 (Box 365, Folder 8)
  - Barnes, Walter Carl, 1931-39 (Box 365, Folder 9)
  - Barney, Isabelle Williams, 1926-35 (Box 365, Folder 10)
  - Barnhardt, F. K., 1920 (Box 365, Folder 11)
  - Barr-Barz (misc), 1917-28 (Box 365, Folder 12)
  - Barr, Alfred H., Jr., 1926-32 (Box 365, Folder 13)
  - Barragon, Lucy Lord '00, 1926-32 (Box 365, Folder 14)
  - Barry, Florence ex '35, 1932-37 (Box 365, Folder 15)
  - Barton, Blake, 1933-35 (Box 365, Folder 16)
  - Bas-Baz (misc), 1919-38 (Box 365, Folder 17)
  - Bassett, John Spencer, 1922-36 (Box 365, Folder 18)
  - Baum, Paul F., 1917-21 (Box 365, Folder 19)
  - Baxter, James P., 1938 (Box 365, Folder 20)
  - Bea-Bel (misc), 1917-45; undated (Box 366, Folder 1)
  - Becker, Howard, 1932-39 (Box 366, Folder 2)
  - Beebe, Ruth White, 1936 (Box 366, Folder 3)
  - Beets, N., 1921-29 (Box 366, Folder 4)
  - Belden, Henry Adams, 1921-35 (Box 366, Folder 5)
  - Bem-Bern (misc), 1917-43; undated (Box 366, Folder 6)
  - Benezet, Louis P., 1921-38 (Box 366, Folder 7)
  - Bennett, Sidney K., 1934 (Box 366, Folder 8)
  - Bernard, Frances Fenton, 1920-29 (Box 366, Folder 9)
  - Bernard, I. H., 1925 (Box 366, Folder 10)
  - Bernbaum, Ernest, 1917-36 (Box 366, Folder 11)
  - Berr-Bez (misc), 1920-41; undated (Box 366, Folder 12)
  - Bi (misc), 1918-39; undated (Box 366, Folder 13)
  - Bicknell, Harry E., 1922-23 (Box 366, Folder 14)
  - Bigelow, Harriet Williams, 1922-23 (Box 366, Folder 15)
  - Bildersee, Isaac (Box 366, Folder 16)
  - Billikopf, Jacob, 1927-42 (Box 366, Folder 17)
  - Billington, Ray Allen, 1937-39 (Box 366, Folder 18)
  - Binkley, Robert C., 1929-36 (Box 366, Folder 19)
  - Bixler, Julius Seelye, 1926-41 (Box 366, Folder 20)
  - Bl (misc), 1918-39; undated (Box 366, Folder 21)
  - Blake, Helen P., 1926-27 (Box 366, Folder 22)
  - Blake, Mabelle Babcock, 1925-33 (Box 366, Folder 23)
  - Blake, Norman H., 1929 (Box 366, Folder 24)
  - Blakeslee, Margaret (Bridges) '06, 1928-30 (Box 366, Folder 25)
  - Blayney, Lindsey, 1924-26 (Box 366, Folder 26)
  - Bliss, Homer C., 1924-33 (Box 366, Folder 27)
  - Bliss, Laura Adella, 1920-23 (Box 366, Folder 28)
  - Boa-Bon (misc), 1916-39; undated (Box 367, Folder 1)
  - Boaz, Franz, 1919-39 (Box 367, Folder 2)
  - Boie, Mildred Louise, 1935-36 (Box 367, Folder 3)
  - Boland, James P., 1934-35 (Box 367, Folder 4)
  - Boo-Bour (misc), 1917-39; undated (Box 367, Folder 5)
  - Borgese, G. Antonio, 1924-39 (Box 367, Folder 6)
  - Boulanger, Nadia, 1936-37 (Box 367, Folder 7)
  - Bourland, Caroline Brown '93, 1917-39 (Box 367, Folder 8)
  - Bous-Boz (misc), 1919-39; undated (Box 367, Folder 9)
  - Bra (misc), 1920-39; undated (Box 367, Folder 10)
  - Bradley, Oliver B., 1914-34 (Box 367, Folder 11)
  - Bradford, Stella, 1923-33 (Box 367, Folder 12)
  - Bradshaw, Margaret Rooker, 1922-30 (Box 367, Folder 13)
  - Bradshaw, Jane, 1931-32 (Box 367, Folder 14)
  - Brady, John Everett, 1919-36 (Box 367, Folder 15)
  - Bragdon, Helen (Cobb) '07, 1928-39 (Box 367, Folder 16)
  - Branch, Anna Hempstead '97, 1933-37 (Box 367, Folder 17)
  - Brawley, Benjamin, 1918-30 (Box 367, Folder 18)
  - Bre-Bri (misc), 1913-40; undated (Box 367, Folder 19)
  - Bree, Germaine, 1932-37 (Box 367, Folder 20)
  - Breed, Nathaniel P. and Effie T., 1926-27 (Box 367, Folder 21)
  - Brewster, Achsah (Barlow) '02, 1921-23 (Box 367, Folder 22)
  - Briggs, L. B. R., 1918-23 (Box 367, Folder 23)
  - Briggs, Lucia R., 1924-39 (Box 367, Folder 24)
  - Bro-Bry (misc), 1917-39; undated (Box 367, Folder 25)
  - Broadhurst, Tom and Iva, 1921-37 (Box 367, Folder 26)
  - Broadus, Edmund K., 1917-37 (Box 367, Folder 27)
  - Broch, Hermann, 1941 (Box 367, Folder 28)
  - Brown, Adelaide '88, 1917-36 (Box 367, Folder 29)
  - Brown, Carleton, 1918-39 (Box 367, Folder 30)
  - Brown, Charles A., 1925 (Box 367, Folder 31)
  - Brown, Dorothy Kirchwey, 1935 (Box 367, Folder 32)
  - Brown, Dorothy Miles, 1920-22 (Box 367, Folder 33)
  - Brown, Theodore E., 1926-35 (Box 367, Folder 34)
  - Brown, Vera Lee, 1929-36 (Box 367, Folder 35)
  - Brown, W. Rolfe, 1930-35 (Box 367, Folder 36)
  - Browne, Nina Eliza '82, 1918-36 (Box 367, Folder 37)
  - Brunton, Francis Arjuna, 1933-34 (Box 367, Folder 38)
  - Bryson, Gladys Eugenia, 1931-39 (Box 367, Folder 39)
  - Bu-By (misc), 1919-39; undated (Box 367, Folder 40)
  - Burch, Katharine '31, 1930 (Box 367, Folder 41)
  - Burnett, Edith, 1932-39 (Box 367, Folder 42)
  - Burt, C. Pauline, 1927-30 (Box 367, Folder 43)
  - Burton, Marion Leroy and Nina M., 1917-28 (Box 367, Folder 44)
  - Butt, S. McClellan, 1930-38 (Box 367, Folder 45)
  - Bye, Arthur E., 1932 (Box 367, Folder 46)
  - Cab-Cap (misc), 1921-39; undated (Box 368, Folder 1)
  - Cable, George W. and Hannah, 1925-34 (Box 368, Folder 2)
  - Cahoon, Jean Clark '11, 1924-36 (Box 368, Folder 3)
  - Canaday, Frank H., 1936 (Box 368, Folder 4)
  - Cann, Jessie Yeareance, 1918-36 (Box 368, Folder 5)
  - Car-Caz (misc), 1920-39; undated (Box 368, Folder 6)
  - Carlisle, Florence Jeffrey, 1925-36 (Box 368, Folder 7)
  - Carmichael, Leonard, 1926-36 (Box 368, Folder 8)
  - Cather, Willa, 1933; undated (Box 368, Folder 9)
  - Cattanes, Helene, 1923-39 (Box 368, Folder 10)
  - Caverno, Julia Harwood '87, 1918-31 (Box 368, Folder 11)
  - Cayley, Harry G., 1934-39 (Box 368, Folder 12)
  - Ce-Chap (misc), 1920-41; undated (Box 368, Folder 13)
  - Cecil, Robert, 1921-23 (Box 368, Folder 14)
  - Chalmers, Andrew Burns, 1935-39 (Box 368, Folder 15)
  - Chapin, Anne McClallan '04, 1922-29 (Box 368, Folder 16)
  - Chapin, F. Stuart, 1919-26 (Box 368, Folder 17)
  - Char-Chy (misc), 1921-39; undated (Box 368, Folder 18)
  - Chase, Ethel Withington '02, 1922-24 (Box 368, Folder 19)
  - Chase, Mary Ellen, 1925-39; undated (Box 368, Folder 20)
  - Chase, Stanley, 1919-35 (Box 368, Folder 21)
  - Cheney, Frances E., 1923-27 (Box 368, Folder 22)
  - Cheney, Warren, 1934 (Box 368, Folder 23)
  - Chew, Samuel C. and Adele K., 1924-35 (Box 368, Folder 24)
  - Childs, Ralph de Someri, 1926-32; undated (Box 368, Folder 25)
  - Chilton, Eleanor Carroll '12, 1922-28; undated (Box 368, Folder 26)
  - Churchill, Alfred Vance, 1917-36; undated (Box 368, Folder 27-29)
  - Ci-Cl (misc), 1917-39; undated (Box 368, Folder 30)
  - Claflin, Janet, 1933-36; undated (Box 368, Folder 31)
  - Clark, Annetta Isabel '04, 1920-43 (Box 368, Folder 32)
  - Clark, John Bates, 1920-27 (Box 368, Folder 33)
  - Clark, Julia ex '10, 1931 (Box 368, Folder 34)
  - Clark, Marguerite Dixon '06, 1926-39; undated (Box 368, Folder 35)
  - Clarke, Elizabeth (Lawrence) '83, 1920-33 (Box 368, Folder 36)
  - Closson, William Baxter, 1927-29 (Box 368, Folder 37)
  - Coa-Col (misc), 1920-39; undated (Box 368, Folder 38)
  - Cobb, Mary, 1917-21 (Box 368, Folder 39)
  - Coburn, Anne Cutter '21, 1928-38 (Box 368, Folder 40)
  - Coe, Ada M., 1936-39 (Box 368, Folder 42)
  - Coffin, Henry Sloane, 1928-33 (Box 368, Folder 43)
  - Cohen, Morris, Mary, and Leonora '30, 1925-39 (Box 368, Folder 44)
  - Collins, Elizabeth Maud, 1929-39 (Box 368, Folder 45)
  - Collins, Robert Frank, 1928-37 (Box 368, Folder 46)
  - Com-Con (misc), 1919-37; undated (Box 369, Folder 1)
  - Comstock, Ada Louise '97, 1917-43 (Box 369, Folder 2-3)
  - Conant, James B. and Grace R., 1930-39 (Box 369, Folder 4)
  - Cone, Ethel Woolverton '07, 1922-34 (Box 369, Folder 5)
  - Conklin, Bertha (Robe) '04, 1919-28 (Box 369, Folder 6)
  - Coo-Coz (misc), 1918-39; undated (Box 369, Folder 7)
  - Cook, Alice Rice '21, 1930-36 (Box 369, Folder 8)
  - Cook, Walter W. S., 1935-38 (Box 369, Folder 9)
  - Coolidge, Calvin, 1918-32 (Box 369, Folder 10)
  - Coolidge, Cora Helen '92, 1920-31 (Box 369, Folder 11)
  - Coolidge, Julian L., 1922-36 (Box 369, Folder 12)
  - Copeland, Charles Townsend, 1925-28 (Box 369, Folder 13)
  - Corbett, Alta Smith '08, 1930-39 (Box 369, Folder 14)
  - Cordes, Paul, 1936-39 (Box 369, Folder 15)
  - Corwin, Margaret, 1934-35 (Box 369, Folder 16)
  - Cory, Herbert Ellsworth, 1922-26 (Box 369, Folder 17)
  - Cowling, Donald, 1929-33 (Box 369, Folder 18)
  - Cr (misc), 1915-41; undated (Box 369, Folder 19)
  - Craig, Hardin, 1925-32 (Box 369, Folder 20)
  - Crane, Esther '10, 1925-36 (Box 369, Folder 21)
  - Crook, Margaret Brackenbury, 1921-39 (Box 369, Folder 22)
  - Cu-Cz (misc), 1917-39; undated (Box 369, Folder 23)
  - Curti, Margaret Wooster, 1928-39 (Box 369, Folder 24)
  - Curti, Merle Eugene, 1922-38 (Box 369, Folder 25)
  - Cutler, Anna Alice '85, 1926-37 (Box 369, Folder 26)
  - Da-Dau (misc), 1920-40; undated (Box 369, Folder 27)
  - Dale, Esther Ellen, 1918-21 (Box 369, Folder 28)
  - Darr, John Whittier and Vera C., 1925-37 (Box 369, Folder 29)
  - Dav-Daz (misc), 1917-40; undated (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Davenport, Charles N., 1926-32 (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - Davenport, Ellen (Emerson) '01, 1921-23 (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - David, Florence Didiez, 1919-21 (Box 370, Folder 4)
  - Davidson, Clara Willoughby '05, 1920-31 (Box 370, Folder 5)
  - Davies, Thomas F., 1918-21 (Box 370, Folder 6)
  - Davis, Anna (Paret) '95, 1929-38 (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - Davis, Marian (Rubins) '20 and Horace, 1926-38 (Box 370, Folder 8)
  - Davis, Theodore Lawrence, 1925-26 (Box 370, Folder 9)
  - Dawes, Anna L., 1926-38 (Box 370, Folder 10)
  - Day, Dorothy, 1929-37 (Box 370, Folder 11)
  - Day, Elizabeth (Lewis) '95, 1924-38 (Box 370, Folder 12)
  - De-Del (misc), 1920-41; undated (Box 370, Folder 13)
  - Deane, Helen M., 1930-37 (Box 370, Folder 14)
  - Deane, Sidney Norton, 1919-39 (Box 370, Folder 15)
  - Dedman, Margaret Dennison ex '27, 1924-25 (Box 370, Folder 16)
  - DeForest, Charlotte (Burgis) '01, 1923-36 (Box 370, Folder 17)
  - deKalb, Eugenie (Walker) '18, 1922-34 (Box 370, Folder 18)
  - Delpit, Louise, 1918-39 (Box 370, Folder 19)
  - del Vecchio, Bianca, 1933-39 (Box 370, Folder 20)
  - Dem-Dez (misc), 1919-40; undated (Box 370, Folder 21)
  - de Maetzu, Maria, 1921-37 (Box 370, Folder 22)
  - de Mauriac, Alice Bergen ex '29, 1926 (Box 370, Folder 23)
  - Denman, Helen Charlotte '10, 1925-39 (Box 370, Folder 24)
  - Dennett, Tyler, 1936-37 (Box 370, Folder 25)
  - Denslow, Roy Richard, 1917-25 (Box 370, Folder 26)
  - de Schweinitz, Dorothea '12, 1924-28 (Box 370, Folder 27)
  - Detti, Marietta Emma, 1929-32 (Box 370, Folder 28)
  - de Villelle, Aline, 1928-37; undated (Box 370, Folder 29)
  - Dewey, Robert Merrill, 1921-39 (Box 370, Folder 30)
  - Dey, Mary (Duguid) '84, 1919-34 (Box 370, Folder 31)
  - D'H-Di (misc), 1920-39; undated (Box 370, Folder 32)
  - Dietz, Frederick Charles, 1919-20 (Box 370, Folder 33)
  - Dimnet, Ernest, 1919-23; undated (Box 370, Folder 34)
  - Dixon, Mary Newbury '17, 1928-37 (Box 370, Folder 35)
  - Do (misc), 1919-39; undated (Box 370, Folder 36)
  - Dohrn, Max, 1923-34 (Box 370, Folder 37)
  - Donaldson, John L., 1917- (Box 370, Folder 38)
  - Dondo, Mathurin Marius and Anna, 1918-34 (Box 370, Folder 39)
  - Donini, Ambrogio E., 1929-33 (Box 370, Folder 40)
  - Dorris, Frances Sue '25, 1925-26 (Box 370, Folder 41)
  - Doty, Madeleine Zabriskie '00, 1921-37 (Box 370, Folder 42)
  - Douglas, Dorothy Wolff, 1928-39 (Box 370, Folder 43)
  - Douglas, Paul H., 1924-25 (Box 370, Folder 44)
  - Douglas, Peggy (Zinsser) '19, 1936-39 (Box 370, Folder 45)
  - Dr-Du (misc), 1918-39; undated (Box 371, Folder 1)
  - DuBois, W. E. B., 1933-34 (Box 371, Folder 2)
  - Duckett, Wleanor Shipley, 1919-36; undated (Box 371, Folder 3)
  - Duke, John Woods, 1923-37 (Box 371, Folder 4)
  - Dunham, Mary (Box 371, Folder 5)
  - Dunn, Emmett Reid, 1919-31 (Box 371, Folder 6)
  - Dunn, Esther Cloudman, 1922-39 (Box 371, Folder 7)
  - Dunton, Edith Kellogg '97, 1918-36 (Box 371, Folder 8)
  - Ea-Ei (misc), 1921-39; undated (Box 371, Folder 9)
  - Earle, Dorothy, 1925-26 (Box 371, Folder 10)
  - Eastman, Mary '86, 1917-35 (Box 371, Folder 11)
  - Eddy, Sherwood, 1929-36 (Box 371, Folder 12)
  - Egan, Rose Frances, 1920-35 (Box 371, Folder 13)
  - Eiserhardt, Ewald, 1919-32 (Box 371, Folder 14)
  - Ej-En (misc), 1920-39; undated (Box 371, Folder 15)
  - Eldridge, Seba, 1918- (Box 371, Folder 16)
  - Eliot, Charles William, 1918-35 (Box 371, Folder 17)
  - Eliot, Samuel Atkins, 1918-32 (Box 371, Folder 18)
  - Eliot, Samuel Atkins, Jr., 1918-39 (Box 371, Folder 19)
  - Eliot, T. S., 1921-33 (Box 371, Folder 20)
  - Ellett, Virginia Randolph, 1925-30 (Box 371, Folder 21)
  - Emerson, Anna (Seelye) '89, 1921-45 (Box 371, Folder 22)
  - Emerson, Ellen Tucker '01, 1917-20 (Box 371, Folder 23)
  - Emerson, Josephine (Sewall) '97, 1925-39; undated (Box 371, Folder 24)
  - Emerson, Kendall, 1929-39 (Box 371, Folder 25)
  - Eo-Ez (misc), 1918-39; undated (Box 371, Folder 26)
  - Erskine, John, 1921-38 (Box 371, Folder 27)
  - Estes, James F., 1919-20 (Box 371, Folder 28)
  - Eymer, Esther Louise ex '27, 1925-26 (Box 371, Folder 29)
  - Fa (misc), 1918-40; undated (Box 372, Folder 1)
  - Fabyan, George, 1917-29 (Box 372, Folder 2)
  - Fansler, Harriet Ely, 1925-26 (Box 372, Folder 3)
  - Farrand, Livingston, 1920-39 (Box 372, Folder 4)
  - Farrand, Margaret Louise '14, 1920-29 (Box 372, Folder 5)
  - Faulkner, Harold Underwood, 1925-39 (Box 372, Folder 6)
  - Fay, Sidney Bradshaw and Dorothy, 1918-39 (Box 372, Folder 7)
  - Fe (misc), 1920-39; undated (Box 372, Folder 8)
  - Ferio, Germaine, 1922-36 (Box 372, Folder 9)
  - Ferry, Frederick C., 1921-38 (Box 372, Folder 10)
  - Few, William Preston, 1926-36 (Box 372, Folder 11)
  - Fi (misc), 1918-39; undated (Box 372, Folder 12)
  - Field, Henry P., 1921-37 (Box 372, Folder 13)
  - Finley, John H., 1929-35 (Box 372, Folder 14)
  - Fischer, Luise, 1928-38 (Box 372, Folder 15)
  - Fisher, Alfred Young, 1937-39 (Box 372, Folder 16)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1937-39 (Box 372, Folder 17)
  - Fiske, Minnie Maddern, 1921-28 (Box 372, Folder 18)
  - Fitz-Darby, Delphine, 1930 (Box 372, Folder 19)
  - Fitzgerald, Roy G., 1929 (Box 372, Folder 20)
  - Fl-Fol (misc), 1921-39; undated (Box 372, Folder 21)
  - Foerster, Norman, 1924-25 (Box 372, Folder 22)
  - Folinsbee, Ruth (Baldwin) '12 and John F., 1927-37 (Box 372, Folder 23)
  - Foley, Edna Lois '01, 1925-35 (Box 372, Folder 24)
  - Foo-For (misc), 1919-38; undated (Box 372, Folder 25)
  - Forbes, M. E., 1925-29 (Box 372, Folder 26)
  - Ford, Harriet (Bliss) '99, 1927-39 (Box 372, Folder 27-28)
  - Ford, J. D. M., 1926-37 (Box 372, Folder 29)
  - Fos-Foz (misc), 1919-39; undated (Box 372, Folder 30)
  - Fosdick, Harry Emerson, 1924-38 (Box 372, Folder 31)
  - Foster, Mary Louise '91, 1920-39 (Box 372, Folder 32)
  - Foulche-Delbosc, Isabel, 1936-37 (Box 372, Folder 33)
  - Fox, Dixon Ryan, 1931-37 (Box 372, Folder 34)
  - Fra (misc), 1920-39; undated (Box 373, Folder 1)
  - Francis, Vida Hunt '92, 1922-34 (Box 373, Folder 2)
  - Francke, Kuno, 1923-26 (Box 373, Folder 3)
  - Frankfurter, Felix and Marian (Denman) '12, 1921-41 (Box 373, Folder 4)
  - Franklin, Lucy J., 1925-38 (Box 373, Folder 5)
  - Fre-Fry (misc), 1922-39; undated (Box 373, Folder 6)
  - Frederick, Frank B., 1934 (Box 373, Folder 7)
  - Fu-Fz (misc), 1919-39; undated (Box 373, Folder 8)
  - Fuller, Mary Breese '94, 1919-29 (Box 373, Folder 9)
  - Ga (misc), 1917-40; undated (Box 373, Folder 10)
  - Gabel, Leona Christine, 1928-39 (Box 373, Folder 11)
  - Galbraith, Archibald Victor, 1927-39 (Box 373, Folder 12)